Searchable local memory for AI agents
VectorLane v0.1.0
$ vectorlane init
Storage initialized at ~/.vectorlane
$ vectorlane ingest demo/docs --collection talocode
Ingested 3 documents 43 chunks
Embeddings: local-hash 256 dimensions
Offline. No API key required.
$ vectorlane search "How does GateLane control tools?" --citations
Results
1. GateLane uses a tool-policy registry to control agent tool access
score: 0.94   cite: docs/gatelane.md L42
2. Tool access is gated by a permission check at runtime
score: 0.87   cite: src/gate.ts L18
3. Each agent declares tools in lane.json at startup
score: 0.79   cite: config/lane.json L7
Integrations
MemoryLane import  |  ContextLane import
$ vectorlane import-memorylane ./export.json
VectorLane - open-source local vector memory engine
npm install -g @talocode/vectorlane